ANS Record Group 2: Curatorial, 1858-ongoing
ANS Archives
- Series 18: William E. Metcalf curator correspondence, 1954-2000, bulk 1982-2000; 10 cubic feet (10 boxes)
  - Box 4 of 10
    - CIN (Commission Internationale de Numismatique), 1954-1979
    - CIN (Commission Internationale de Numismatique), 1991
    - CIN (Commission Internationale de Numismatique), 1991-1993
    - INC (International Numismatic Conference)—Berlin, 1997
    - Kenneth Jonsson—Numismatic computer project, 1992-1994
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art—Money in the Byzantine World, 1997
  - Box 5 of 10
    - Antioch project, 1998-1999
    - Israel loan, 1998
    - Late antiquity – Bowersock, Brown, and Grabar, 1997
    - APIS (Advanced Papyrological Information System) and seminar alumni forms
    - Reader’s reports, 1997
    - New curator position, 1995
    - APA (American Philological Association) – Affiliated groups, 1994
    - San Francisco Mint visit, 1994
    - ANS bylaws and curatorial policies and procedures, 1989-1990
    - Severan Caesarea
    - Princeton, 1998-1999
    - New York Numismatic Club, 1994-1995
    - Milan, 1992
    - Kyrenia Girdle
    - John Humphry, 1992
    - Notes
    - Lycia notes
    - Macmillan Dictionary of Art, 1993-1994
    - George His, 1997-1998
    - Icomon, 1994
    - Executive Committee, 1995
    - Harvard University Press, 1997-1998
    - Munich/Warsaw, 1994
    - Jennifer Sheridan, 1990-1991
    - Dave Wuchinch, 1990
    - Yankees, 1989
    - Charles K. Williams II gift, 1982
    - Velleius
    - A.E. Housman
    - William S. Kable, 1996
    - Jeremy J. Stone, 1997
    - Princeton, 1997
    - Alice-Mary Talbot, 1998
    - RNS (Royal Numismatic Society), 1996
    - Fellows, 1997
    - Document requests
    - Personal study, 1997
    - CNL (Colonial Newsletter), 1995-1996
    - AAM (American Association of Museums), 1991-1997
    - Coin World – Michael Hodder, 1992-1993
    - Green binder with coin descriptions – Alexandria, Tyre, Judaea, Antioch, Ephesus, Byzantium
    - Hadrian AV
    - Anonymous AE
    - Andrea Saccocci, 1996
    - Edict, 1994
    - Cyprus
    - Columbia University, 1993-1996
    - CNG (Classical Numismatic Group), 1998
    - Joshua D. Sosin, 1998
    - Nataliya M. Smirnova, 1994
    - ANS Funds – Background, covers 1908-1989
    - Development dossiers, 1994
    - Friends of Ancient History, 1994-1996
  - Box 6 of 10
    - A, 1985-1989
    - AIA, APA, AHA – RSVPs, 1987-1988
    - AIA, 1989
    - AHA, 1987-1988
    - AIA/APA – San Antonio, Texas, 1986
    - American Academy in Rome, 1985-1988
    - American Philological Association, 1985-1988
    - AJA (American Journal of Archaeology)
    - Archaeological Congress – Baltimore, Maryland, 1988-1989
    - Archaeological Institute of America, 1979-1988
    - Audubon Terrace, 1985
    - B, 1986-1990
    - Harry W. Bass, Jr., 1981-1982
    - Glen W. Bowersock, 1983-1988
    - Beloit College, 1987-1988
    - Biographies for W.E. Metcalf, 1987
    - Theodore V. Buttrey, 1981-1988
    - C, 1985-1989
    - Giles Carter, 1986-1988
    - Carter/Metcalf, 1987
    - C. Daniel Clark, 1973-1989
    - Frank Clover, 1987
    - Coin dealers, 1986
    - Columbia University, 1971-1988
    - Columbia University Collection, 1984
    - Curriculum Vitae, 1987-1988
    - D, 1985-1989
    - Ben Damsky, 1987-1988
    - E, 1985-1988
    - Jane DeRose Evans, 1986-1989
    - George Ewing, 1986-1988
    - F, 1985-1989
    - Harry W. Fowler, 1983-1988
    - G, 1984-1990
    - H, 1985-1989
    - Wolfgang Hahn, 1984-1989
    - Michael Hendy, 1988
    - High Museum of Art, 1985
    - Huntington medal, 1979-1980
    - John Humphrey, 1982-1988
    - Helene Huvelin, 1985-1987
    - I, 1986-1988
    - J, 1986-1989
    - J, 1986-1989
    - J. Paul Getty Museum, 1984
    - Martha Joukousky, 1986
    - K, 1985-1988
    - Fred S. Kleiner, 1985-1989
    - L, 1985-1989
    - Lexicon Iconogaphicum, 1985-1988
    - Lexicon Iconographicum, 1979-1983
    - Loan Request Forms (blank)
  - Box 7 of 10
    - M, 1985-1990
    - Mc, 1986-1989
    - William E. Metcalf, 1988
    - William E. Metcalf – Seminar handouts
    - William E. Metcalf – Curriculum Vitae and photograph portrait
    - Leo Mildenberg, 1987-1988
    - Leo Mildenberg, 1987-1988
    - N, 1987-1989
    - O, 1985-1989
    - P, 1986-1989
    - Michael Peachin, 1981-1986
    - Professional Numismatics Guild, 1965-1984
    - Q, 1987
    - R, 1985-1990
    - S, 1980-1990
    - T, 1985-1989
    - Tampa Museum, 1983-1984
    - Margaret Thompson—Death, 1992
    - Travelers Company – Coin insurance claim case, 1988
    - V, 1985-1989
    - Terrance Volk, 1984
    - W, 1982-1991
    - Malcolm B. Wallace, 1976-1977
    - XYZ, 1987-1990
    - Warrants for purchased coins, 1989-1990
    - Endowment Medal distribution, 1989
    - NAME (National Association for Museum Exhibition), 1998
    - Museum associations, 1995-1998
    - Events – Flyers, 1995-1997
    - Numismatic Literature, 1994
    - Renovations, 1990-1992
    - AJN (American Journal of Numismatics), 1999
    - AJN (American Journal of Numismatics) – Reviews, 1999
    - ANS move from Audubon Terrace, 1994-1995
    - Roger Bland – British Museum, 1989-1997
    - Jeremiah Brady, 1979-1980
    - George Depeyrot, 1993
    - Daniel M. Friedenberg, 1997
    - Haim Gitler, 1995-1996
    - Arthur Houghton, 1993-1995
    - Silvia Hurter, 1995-1999
    - John M. Kleeberg, 1990-1997
    - John H. Kroll, 1995-1997
    - Henry Clay Lindgren, 1994
    - Donald Partrick, 1993-1996
    - Alan Stahl, 1993-2000
    - Carlos A. Verdi, 1991-1993
  - Box 8 of 10
    - Curatorial assistant, 1989
    - E.J. Brill, 1996
    - Andrew Burnett, 1992-1996
    - Comfortable Computing, 1996
    - Michael Bates, 1996-1988
    - Theodore Buttrey, 1995-1998
    - Cyprus – INC (International Numismatic Commission), 1994-1995
    - Shirlee Loret, 1992-1994
    - William S. Kable, 1994
    - P.J. Casey, 1996
    - Kevin Butcher, 1994-1995
    - Green binder—Ancient coin catalog
    - Black binder—Coin purchase funds—detailed on ledger pages, 1980-1981
    - 1982
    - 1983
    - 1983-1984
    - 1984-1985, A-M
    - 1984-1985, N-Z
    - 1986 (1)
    - 1986 (2)
    - 1987
  - Box 9 of 10
    - 1989, A-J
    - 1989, K-Z
    - 1990, A-G
    - 1990, H-Z
    - 1991, A-E
    - 1991, F-M
    - 1991, N-Z
    - 1992, A-F
    - 1992, G-M
    - 1992, N-Z
    - 1994
  - Box 10 of 10
    - 1995, A-K
    - 1995, L-Z
    - 1996, A-K
    - 1996, L-Z
    - 1997-1999, A-E
    - 1997-1999, F-K
    - 1997-1999, L-M
    - 1997-1999, N-R
    - 1997-1999, S-Z
- Series 19: Miscellaneous curatorial records, 1900-1940; 1 box
  Inventories; Correspondence; Photographs; Gorman, Michael
  Various materials relating to ANS coin and other collections. Contains two handwritten inventories, one entitled “List of Pamphlets Etc. on Bottom of Case” (2 pages) and the other a listing by section coins contained in a cabinet (27 pages) (circa 1900); an inventory of ANS token and store card holdings (circa 1903); a list of duplicate coins from the numismatic section of the Public Library, Museum, and Art Gallery of South Australia; photographs, a clipping, and descriptions relating to a theft of medals, including life-saving medals, from the ANS (1939) (includes a receipt and letters relating to a gift from Captain Michael Gorman, 1911-1912); and correspondence resulting from an attempt to contact people who had mailed in coins unsolicited nearly thirty years earlier (1940).
  - Pamphlet and coin inventories, circa 1900
  - ANS token and store card holdings and accessions, ca. 1903
  - Public Library, Museum, and Art Gallery of South Australia--Offer and list of duplicate coins
  - Coin theft, 1939
  - Correspondence regarding unclaimed coins and other items, 1940